http://www.scottishfoodoverseas.com/privacy

My Basket
You have no items in your shopping cart.
Search:
Search
Menu
Home
HampersCreate Your Own
Food & Drink Drinks WhiskiesWineChampagneBeerPort, Gin & LiqueursGinger WineSoft DrinksTea & CoffeeFresh Food CheeseSmoked MeatsMacsween HaggisSmoked SalmonMeat Pies & Black PuddingBurns NightSavoury Food Baxters SoupCondiments & SeasoningCrisps & NutsOatcakesPatePorridgeTinned HaggisSweet Food BiscuitsCakesClootie DumplingsConfectioneryJams and PreservesLuxury ChocolatesShortbreadChristmas FoodBrandsCorporateOccasions Christmas Hampers Birthday HampersThank You HampersFamily HampersFather's Day HampersTheme Whisky HampersGin HampersCheese and Wine HampersAlcohol Free HampersInternational Delivery to AustraliaDelivery to EuropeDelivery to the USADelivery to CanadaDelivery to New ZealandDelivery to ScotlandDelivery to UK-England, Wales and Northern Ireland
Home
Privacy
Privacy and Cookie Policy for Scottish Food and Hampers
Scottish Food and Hampers (a subsidiary of Endrick Trading Ltd) is committed to respecting the privacy rights of visitors to its website. This privacy policy explains how we collect, store and use personal data about you in connection with your use of the website at www.ScottishFoodandHampers.co.uk (the "Website").
It provides you with details about the types of personal data that we collect from you, how we use your personal data and the rights you have to control our use of your personal data.
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.
This policy applies regardless of how the Website is accessed and will cover any technologies or devices by which Scottish Food & Hampers (Endrick Trading Ltd) make the Website available to you.
Please read this privacy policy carefully.  If you do not want your data to be used as set out in this privacy policy, you should not use this Website.
Who we are
ScottishFoodandHampers.co.uk is part of Endrick Trading Ltd which is a company registered in Scotland (registration number SC258572). Our registered office is at 14 Dunmore Street, Balfron, Stirling, Scotland, G63 0TX.  We respect your right to privacy and will only process personal data you provide to us in accordance with GDPR and all other applicable privacy laws.
Data Protection Officer Information
Contact Scottish Food and Hampers at by email or by writing to Data Protection, Endrick Trading Ltd, 14 Dunmore Street, Balfron, Stirling, G63 0TX, Scotland.
Why we collect your data
When you shop on the Scottish Food and Hampers Site, we will ask you to input and we will collect personal information such as your name, email address, billing address, delivery address,
telephone number, product selections, payment method and account password.
We collect this data to:
Process your order
Administer this website
Send periodic emails, primarily for marketing purposed including but not limited to product offers and news about our latest gift ideas.
We also gather statistical and other analytical information on an aggregate basis of all visitors to our website.  The data comprises information that cannot be used to identify or contact a user, such as demographic information, for example
User IP addresses
Browser types
Anonymous  statistical data involving the use of our website
This information is solely used to gain a more informed understanding of how our online store is being used and how can we improve our customer experience.
Who receives your data
The recipients of the data are the Endrick Trading Ltd (permanent, fixed term, contract and trainee staff) who process the data only in the way that have been defined in the “why we collect data’ section. Each staff member has been educated and trained in the importance of the GDPR.
How you can control your data
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:
Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, you will be asked to confirm you have read our Terms and Conditions, which includes details on the data we collect and how we use it. By confirming you have read our Terms and Conditions, you give us consent to use your personal details to process your order and complete administration on the website. You will NOT receive marketing communications from Endrick Trading unless you provide consent.
You can opt-in to receive a newsletter with our latest gift ideas, free delivery vouchers and promotions, by providing your name and email in our Subscribe form. You may change your mind at any time by clicking UNSUBSCRIBE on a newsletter.
You can request to correct, amend or delete information we hold about you by writing to Endrick Trading Ltd., 14 Dunmore Street, Balfron, Stirlingshire, G63 0TX or emailing us at office@endricktrading.co.uk. Unless it is prohibited by law, we will remove any Personal Information about you, from our servers at your request. There is no charge for an individual to update their Personal Information.
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you. If you would like a copy, please write to Endrick Trading Ltd., 14 Dunmore Street, Balfron, Stirlingshire, G63 0TX or by email.
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
You have the right to withdraw consent for us holding your data any time. Please write to or email us at the above address. We will promptly delete your personal information from our systems (the only exception to this being our compliance to legal obligations – please see below) .
How long your data is stored
Scottish Food and Hampers will retain personal data for the following reasons:
Data that is required to process your order. This will be held on our systems for a seven-year period following completion for our tax records.
For legitimate business interests (as defined in purposes and legal basis of the processing). Data that is no longer deemed necessary will be deleted from our system
When personal data is deemed no longer necessary, it will be removed an deleted in a correct manner.
Protecting your data
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure.
In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
If a data breach has occurred which compromises your personal data, you will be informed within 72 hours of first having become aware of the breach.
Third Party Services
Google Analytics When someone visits this Site we use a third-party service, Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be upfront about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.
The data collected by Google Analytics is deleted after 3 years.
E-newsletter
We use a third party provider, MailChimp, to deliver e-newsletters. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies including clear gifs to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter. For more information, please see MailChimp's Privacy Policy.
WordPress
We use a third party service, WordPress.com, to publish our blog. This site is hosted at WordPress.com, which is run by Automattic Inc. We use a standard WordPress service to collect anonymous information about users' activity on the site, for example the number of users viewing pages on the site, to monitor and report on the effectiveness of the site and help us improve it. WordPress requires visitors that want to post a comment to enter a name and email address. For more information about how WordPress processes data, please see Automattic's privacy notice.
LiveChat service
We use a third party provider, DDI group, to supply and support our LiveChat service, which we use to handle customer enquiries in real time.
If you use the LiveChat service we will collect your name, email address (optional) and the contents of your LiveChat session. This information will be retained for 6 months and will not be shared with any other organisations. You can request a transcript of your Live Chat session if you provide your email address at the start of your session or when prompted at the end. Please see DDI Group's Privacy Policy for further details.
Payment processing
We use WorldPay and Paypal to process your payments. You can read their privacy policies here.
World Pay Privacy Policy
PayPal Privacy Policy (UK)
Trusted Shops
We use a third-party provider, Trusted Shops, to collect feedback from our customers.
Once you have completed an order, Trusted Shops collects your IP address, the date and time of order, the products order, the data volume transferred and the requesting provider (access data), and documents the retrieval. This data is not evaluated and is automatically deleted seven days after your visit to the Check Out.
Other personal information will only be transferred to Trusted Shops if you decide, after completing an order, to use Trusted Shops products or have already registered for their use. In this case, the contractual agreement between you and Trusted Shops applies.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Updates to this policy
This privacy policy was last updated in April 2018. Please check back regularly to keep informed of updates to this privacy policy.
Contact us
If you have any questions please write to Endrick Trading Ltd. 14 Dunmore Street, Balfron, Stirlingshire, G63 0TX or email using this contact form.
Payment processing
We use WorldPay and Paypal to process your payments. You can read their privacy policies here.
World Pay Privacy Policy
PayPal Privacy Policy (UK)
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Updates to this policy
This privacy policy was last updated in March 2018. Please check back regularly to keep informed of updates to this privacy policy.
Contact us
If you have any questions please write to Endrick Trading Ltd. 14 Dunmore Street, Balfron, Stirlingshire, G63 0TX or email using this contact form.
Cookie Policy
Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer when you visit most websites. They are sent back and forth between the website’s server and your Internet browser to allow the website to remember actions you’ve made. If you continue without changing your settings, we’ll assume that you are happy to receive all cookies on scottishfoodandhampers.co.uk.
We use cookies and other local storage means to help improve the performance of this website by measuring web traffic and tracking user journeys.
Cookies set up by this website
During any visit to Scottishfoodandhampers.co.uk, the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your device. Many websites do this because cookies enable website publishers to do useful things like finding out whether the device (and probably its user) has visited the website before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit.
Information supplied by cookies can help us to understand the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience and improve Scottishfoodandhampers.co.uk’s services provided to users.
Google Analytics
Scottishfoodandhampers.co.uk cookies set by Google Analytics to collect information about how our visitors use this site. This data is collected anonymously and is used to help improve this website’s functionality. For more information on which cookies are used, see Google Analytic’s page on safeguarding your data.
Third Party Cookies on ScottishFoodandHampers.co.uk
Social Media
We sometimes embed content from social media and other third-party websites. These may include YouTube, Vimeo, Twitter, Facebook and Instagram. As a result, when you visit a page containing such content, you may be presented with cookies from these websites and these third-party cookies may track your use of the Scottish Food and Hampers' website. ScottishFoodandHampers.co.uk does not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third party’s website for more information.
Trusted Shops
We use a third-party provider, Trusted Shops, to collect feedback from our customers. Once you have completed an order, Trusted Shops collects your IP address, the date and time of order, the products order, the data volume transferred and the requesting provider (access data), and documents the retrieval. This data is not evaluated and is automatically deleted seven days after your visit to the Check Out. Other personal information will only be transferred to Trusted Shops if you decide, after completing an order, to use Trusted Shops products or have already registered for their use. In this case, the contractual agreement between you and Trusted Shops applies
Managing Cookie Preferences
Most Internet browsers allow users to control the acceptance of cookies via the browser’s settings. You can modify your browser settings to decline cookies if you prefer, although this may prevent you from taking full advantage of a website. Each browser version works in a slightly different way, but you generally have the ability to accept all cookies, be notified before accepting a cookie, block or restrict cookies from certain sites, or reject all cookies.
Visit allaboutcookies.org to find out how to configure these settings on a number of major browsers.
You can opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites by installing Google’s opt-out browser add-on.
Changes to the Cookie and Privacy Policy
We keep our privacy notice under regular review. This cookie policy was last updated on 14 June 2018.
Delicious, seasonal offers and discounts, subscribe to our newsletter.
See our privacy policy to understand how we process your personal data to send you marketing emails
© Copyright Endrick Trading 2011 - 2020 Registered in Scotland - SC258572
Ecommerce by Clydewire Ltd
